submitstart.com 2014-06-29

# Privacy Policy - SubmitStart

« Back to start

## Privacy Policy

SubmitStart believes that a strong privacy is very important for a future success of the web site. We guarantee that SubmitStart will not provide your personal data to anyone else besides the actual search engines that we send your submission to. When we do present information to our advertisers, unless you tell us otherwise, it is in the form of aggregate statistics compiled among all of our visitors' answers to survey questions as well as grouped on-site behavior.

### What information does SubmitStart gather/track and how is it used?

#### Use of traffic data

At SubmitStart, when you are making a submission, we collect the domain name, referral data, and browser and platform type (e.g., a Firefox browser on a Macintosh platform). The SubmitStart site collects visitor information for purposes of product monitoring, product improvement and targeted advertising. We also count, track and aggregate the visitor's activity into our analysis of general traffic flows at our sites (e.g. tracking where traffic comes from, how traffic flows within the SubmitStart properties, etc.). To these ends, we may merge information about you into group data, which may then be shared on an aggregated basis with our advertisers; but SubmitStart will not disclose your individual identity or personal data without your permission. When SubmitStart does present aggregated information to outside companies, no one will be able to identify you or contact you.

#### Use of cookies

SubmitStart may use cookies for internal reporting. Cookies are a standard Internet technology that allow us to both store and retrieve login information on a user's system. Other companies which place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that SubmitStart does not control. However, cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines, so these advertisers will not know who you are.

Use of Email and URL Addresses Collected from Search Engine Submission service

Email and URL addresses used for our free search engine submission service are logged in a log file for tracking purposes and will be subject to receive newsletter and/or announcements from SubmitStart or any of its partners. The email addresses and URL addresses are forwarded in real time to various search engines via the search engine submission page. Please note that a few of these search engines may send you an auto response, confirming your submission.

### What is SubmitStart's unsubscribe and data-removal policy?

If you have agreed to allow SubmitStart to make your information available to outside organizations, we will use our reasonably best efforts to ensure that your individual data is no longer distributed by SubmitStart after your removal request. However, SubmitStart is not responsible for the removal of your personal information from third-party lists if you have previously authorized SubmitStart to distribute it.

SubmitStart may introduce new products and services to its users. To the extent these new products and services affect this policy, this policy will be updated.
